Guide to the Diana Trilling Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1924-1996
  - Subseries IV.2: Lionel Trilling, 1960-1996
    This small subseries is composed of records concerning the life of Lionel Trilling, in particular his published pieces and his archive. In regards to his personal papers, there is correspondence concerning the donation of the papers and requests for permission to access them. Files in regards to Lionel Trilling's writings such as copyright renewals, correspondence and contracts with publishing houses, permission to reuse his material, and general information about the Uniform Edition are found in this subseries as well. In addition to these records, this subseries holds material about the impact of Lionel Trilling on Columbia University and the greater academic community. In particular, there is material relating to the Lionel Trilling Award, the Lionel Trilling Seminars, and copies of scholarly work on Lionel Trilling. Included are Lionel Trilling's F.B.I. and government files.
    - Bibliography, 1985 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Copyright Renewals, 1977-1993 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Government Files, 1960-1964 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Lionel Trilling Award, 1976-1992 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Lionel Trilling Papers
      - Donations, 1978-1995 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      - Permissions, 1979-1995 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Requests for Letters, 1976-1982 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Lionel Trilling Seminars
      - 1976-1978 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - 1979-1987 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - 1988-1995 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - New York Psychoanalytic Institute, 1978 September-November (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Permissions
      - General
        - 1979-1986 (Box 55, Folder 4)
        - 1987-1989 (Box 55, Folder 5)
        - 1990-1993 (Box 55, Folder 6)
        - 1994-1996 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Chelsea House, 1984-1989 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Rushdie, Salman, 1989 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Scholarly Work on Lionel Trilling, 1980-1982 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Uniform Edition
      - Autobiographical Lecture, undated, 1970-1978 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence
        - 1976-1978 May (Box 56, Folder 6)
        - 1978 June-1979 (Box 56, Folder 7)
        - 1980-1986 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Printed Material, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Reception, 1980-1981 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Reviews, 1978-1981 (Box 56, Folder 11)
- Series V: Photographs, 1920s-1990s
  Series V contains photographs of the Trilling family and friends. Included are photographs of Lionel Trilling's father and grandfather, David Trilling and Israel Cohen, respectively. There are also photographs of James Trilling and group photographs of the entire family. Portraits of Diana Trilling and publicity photographs for her book Mrs. Harris: The Death of the Scarsdale Diet Doctor are also in this series. Diana Trilling's time at Radcliffe College and Camp Lenore during the 1920s is well represented. While the individuals in many of these earlier pictures are not identified, the atmosphere of the time period and the impact these two places had on Diana Trilling is clear in the composition of the pictures.
  - Bettina and David Sinclair, 1930s (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Camp Lenore, 1922-1924 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Diana Trilling--Portraits, 1982, 1990s (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Diana Trilling--Publicity Photographs, undated, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Family Photographs
    - General, undated, 1933, 1960-1968 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - James Trilling, undated, 1949, 1964-1969, 1980s (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Lionel Trilling, undated, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Friends, undated, 1928 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Radcliffe College, 1920s (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Unknown Individuals, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Unknown Individuals, undated (Box 57, Folder 14 to L to 1)
- Series VI: Audio Visual Material, 1956-1981
  This series holds several interviews. Included are two reel to reels, one of which has Diana Trilling discussing her edited book Reviewing the Forties and the other is an interview of Vladimir Nabokov conducted by Lionel Trilling for the Canadian Broadcasting Company. Also in this series is a film clip from the NBC series "Elder Wise Men." In the clip, Lionel Trilling interviews Ernest Jones about Freud.
  - Audio Cassette--Diana Trilling Speaking with Patricia McCann on WOR Radio, 1981 November 12 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Film--Ernest Jones Interview by Lionel Trilling for NBC Show "Elder Wise Men," 1956 September 23 (Box 58)
  - Reel to Reel--Diana Trilling Interview of Reviewing the Forties, 1978 October 2 (Box 59)
  - Reel to Reel--Vladimir Nabokov Interview by Lionel Trilling for the Canadian Public Broadcasting Company, 1960 (Box 59)